Guide to the Rogers Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Rogers family papers
1734-1856
MS 1092
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.5
The papers consist of correspondence, account books, diaries, and legal and financial papers of the Rogers family of Branford, Connecticut. Family members documented in the collection include a Hartford merchant, Elizur B. Rogers, and a Fair Haven butcher, A. A. Hemmingway.
Rogers family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Diaries purchased in 1952; remainder of the papers given by Marjorie Earle in 1945.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Rogers Family Papers consist of diaries, account books, legal and financial documents, letters, and exercise books of the Rogers family of Branford, Connecticut, from the mid-eighteenth to the mid-nineteenth century. The papers dated earlier than 1820 are all of a legal or financial nature, including deeds, receipts, reports on surveys, and accounts of the administration of estates. The principal items from the later period are tax lists of Branford and North Branford, 1824-1832; account books of Elizur H. Rogers (d. 1849), apparently a merchant in Hartford, 1836-1840, and A. A. Hemmingway, a butcher in Fair Haven, 1852-1853; and diaries of Samuel Rogers (b. 1824), working on the family farm and mill in North Branford, teaching school in Wallingford, and engaging in the dry goods business in New Haven, 1847-1849.
The Rogers Family Papers were received from Marjorie Earle in 1945 except that the diaries were purchased from Whitlock's in 1952.
Biographical / Historical
Samuel Rogers, son of Samuel A. and Esther J. Page Rogers of North Branford, Connecticut, was born in 1824. He worked on the family farm with his father and then moved to Wallingford, Connecticut to teach school. In 1848 Rogers entered into a dry goods partnership in New Haven with Leonard A. Dickinson, under the name Rogers & Dickinson. Later that same year Rogers entered into business with William L. Kilbourn, under the name Rogers & Kilbourn.
Agriculture; Business; Family farms; Families; Branford (Conn.); Connecticut -- Commerce; Fair Haven (New Haven, Conn.); New Haven (Conn.); North Branford (Conn.); Account books; Deeds; Diaries; Surveys; Merchants; Hemmingway, A. A.; Rogers, Elizur H.; Rogers, Samuel, 1824-; Rogers family; Montague Mining and Trading Association
- Inventory
  - Elizur H. Rogers: ledger and account book of his mercantile business in Hartford, 1838 (Box 1)
  - Samuel Rogers: diaries, 1847-1849 (Box 1)
  - Branford tax lists, 1824, 1826-1827 (Box 1)
  - North Branford tax lists, 1832 (Box 1)
  - Montague Mining and Trading Association: by-laws and articles of association, 1849, undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1777-1849 (Box 1)
  - Exercise books, 1843-1844 (Box 1)
  - Account books, undated (Box 1)
  - Legal and financial papers, 1734-1856 (Box 2)
  - Deeds, 1746-1828 (Box 2)
  - A. A. Hemmingway: ledger and daybook of his meat business in Fair Haven, 1852-1853 (Box 3)